Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ nafizahmedchisty (LinkedIn) nachisty.com (Personal) sites.google.com/site/ nafizahmedchisty/ (Portfolio) engg.aiub.edu/faculties/nafiz (Company)

Top Skills

ASIC

FPGA

SoC

Languages

English (Full Professional)

Hindi (Limited Working)

Swedish (Elementary)

Bengali (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Certificate for Supervising one of the top Nine Undergraduate Project & Thesis from the Department of EEE

Certificate for presenting a talk on "Electrical Wiring" on IEEE day 2013

Certificate for delivering a talk on IPR on IEEE day 2014

MSc in System-on-Chip (SOC)

BSc in EEE

Honors-Awards

The Summa Cum Laude

Certificate for a seminar on IEEE Day 2013

Award on IEEE Day 2014

Award for Supervising one of the top Nine Undergraduate Project & Thesis from the Department of EEE

Special Award at IEEE member orientation 2015

Publications

Nafiz Ahmed Chisty

Senior Member, IEEE; Head, Department of EEE, AIUB; Associate Professor, Department of EEE & CoE, AIUB Dhaka, Bangladesh

Summary

Years of Experience: 13 Total Publications: 13 Scientific Affiliations: 07

Reviewer of International Publications: 04

Research interest: Energy Efficient Digital ASIC Implementation, Low Complexity Algorithm Implementation in HDL, FPGA Application in Wireless Communication; Microcontroller based system and Antenna Design.

Technical skills:

- i) Programming Language: VHDL, VERILOG, C, C++, Assembly Language.
- ii) Engineering Software tools: ModelSim, Xilinx ISE Design Suite, Xilinx XPS, MATLAB, SOC Encounter for Place and Route, Prime Time, Design compiler for synthesis, NI Multisim, Proteus, Active HDL, Precision RTL, Synplify, Quartus, Code Composer Studio, AUTOCAD, SPICE, MicroWind, EWB, DSCH, MipsIT Studio, MASM, EMU8086, SimpleScalar simulator, Ansoft Ensemble SV, Cadence Integrated Designing.
- iii) Testing Tools: Logic Analyzer & Pattern Generator for Testing & Verification, Spectrum Analyzer, Network Analyzer.
- iv) FPGA Boards & Others: Xilinx XUP Virtex-II Pro, Xilinx Spartan 3, TMS320C6713,CoolRunner, PIC, Raspberry Pi.

Experience

AIUB

11 years 8 months

Wireless Sensor Tree Network monitoring system through Web Server

IoT Based Solar Powered System for Smart Field Irrigation with Real Time Surveillance for Smart Agriculture in Bangladesh

IoT Based Smart Street Light For Improved Road Safety

Effect of 16 QAM Interleaved Coded Modulation System in AWGN Channel

Study of the Relative Permittivity Response of Metal Nanoantenna at Optical Frequency Head, Department of EEE; Associate Professor, Department of EEE & CoE

October 2018 - Present (5 years 3 months)

Full time teaching Theory and Lab courses for engineering students; Supervising final year thesis students both Graduate and Undergraduate level;

helping the Department with various departmental activities.

Senior Assistant Professor & Special Assistant, Dept. of EEE & CoE, Faculty of Engineering

December 2016 - September 2018 (1 year 10 months)

Full time teaching Theory and Lab courses for engineering students;

Supervising final year thesis students both Graduate and Undergraduate level; helping the Department with various departmental activities.

Assistant Professor & Special Assistant, Dept. of EEE & CoE, Faculty of Engineering

November 2013 - December 2016 (3 years 2 months)

Full time teaching Theory and Lab courses for engineering students;

Supervising final year thesis students both Graduate and Undergraduate level; helping the Department with various departmental activities.

Faculty and Special Assistant, Dept. of EEE & CoE, Faculty of Engineering

May 2013 - October 2013 (6 months)

Full time teaching Theory and Lab courses for engineering students; Supervising final year thesis students; helping the Department with various departmental activities.

Faculty, Dept. of EEE & CoE, Faculty of Engineering May 2012 - May 2013 (1 year 1 month)

Full time teaching Theory and Lab courses for engineering students; Supervising final year thesis students.

IEEE Bangladesh Section EXComm Professional Activity Coordinator February 2016 - February 2017 (1 year 1 month) Bangladesh

Promoting professional activities within IEEE societies & student branches in Bangladesh Section with active participation of IEEE professionals.

Lund University
Exjobb Student
May 2011 - December 2011 (8 months)
Page 2 of 3

Digital ASIC group

Master's Thesis.

AIUB

Lecturer, Dept. of EEE & CoE, Faculty of Engineering January 2006 - August 2008 (2 years 8 months)

Full time teaching Theory and Lab courses for engineering students; Supervising final year thesis students.

Education

Jahangirnagar University
Doctor of Philosophy (PhD), Research · (2019)

Lunds universitet / Lund University
MSc in System-on-Chip (SOC), Engineering

American International University-Bangladesh
BSc in Electrical and Electronic Engineering, Engineering